Guide to the Barbara Karkabi Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Barbara Karkabi Papers
1971-2009
2000-2009
02/2012-003
Karkabi, Barbara Farrar
11.50 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection includes articles written by Karkabi, correspondence, notes and research materials. The collection is divided into ten series: Personal, Articles, Correspondence, Appointment Books, Houston Chronicle, Notes, Multi-Media, Publications, Research, and Ephemera. All series are arranged topically and chronologically.
Biographical Information:
Born Barbara Diane Farrar, she was the daughter of an English immigrant father and a mother of Portuguese descent in New York City on December 6, 1946. Barbara Karkabi worked as a journalist for the Houston Chronicle for thirty years. She attended parochial schools in Manhattan and earned a bachelor's degree in English literature from Syracuse University in 1968. For several years Karkabi worked as a reservations agent for Pan American Airways, travelling extensively around the world, especially to the Middle East and Asia. While living in Beirut, Lebanon in the mid-1970s, she began writing for the English-language newspaper, Daily Star, covering the nation’s civil war. At one point Karkabi was briefly kidnapped with a busload of Japanese travellers by armed Palestine guerillas.
After leaving Beirut, she moved to London, England with her husband Tony Karkabi, a Lebanese travel agent. In London, Barbara worked as a freelance journalist before moving to Houston, Texas in 1977. Before joining the Houston Chronicle, Karkabi wrote for Suburbia-Reporter, a weekly suburban newspaper in the Houston area. In 1979 she began her career with the Chronicle generating feature stories on a variety of topics ranging from health to women and religious issues to trends in the city’s minority communities. An article she wrote in 1990 about river blindness garnered the attention of local philanthropist John Moores. In response to the story, Moores donated $25 million to an effort by a University of Houston optometry professor, William Baldwin, to distribute a highly effective drug to those in need.
Besides her work with the Chronicle, Karkabi also spent time engaged in women’s organizations. She was a long time board member of Friends of Women's Studies, a nonprofit that supports the University of Houston's Women's Studies program and wrote the first story about the Carey C. Shuart Women's Archive and Research Collection at the UH Library. Karkabi also helped found the Association for Women Journalists Houston chapter in the 1990s.
Karkabi passed away on Saturday January 28, 2012, leaving husband Mike Snyder, also a Houston Chronicle reporter and editor, and daughter Megan Snyder, both of Houston, Texas.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Houston Chronicle; University of Houston. Women's Studies Program
Genre/Form of Material:
Appointment books; Articles; Correspondence; Ephemera; Photographs
Personal Name:
Karkabi, Barbara Farrar
Topical Term:
Women journalists -- Texas -- Houston
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
UH Women's Studies Program and Friends Collection (http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=195).
Scope and Contents
This collection includes articles written by Karkabi, correspondence, notes and research materials. The collection is divided into ten series: Personal, Articles, Correspondence, Appointment Books, Houston Chronicle, Notes, Multi-Media, Publications, Research, and Ephemera. All series are arranged topically and chronologically.
Detailed List of Contents
- Personal, id135655
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials directly related to Karkabi. Included are a short biography and a resume submitted for a seminar on youth mental health.
  - Biography, undated; id135709 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Resume, undated; id135710 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Articles, id135656
  This series consists of articles written by Karkabi over her career. The majority of the articles were written for the Houston Chronicle, but the series also contains articles published in other newspapers and noted as such.
  - Animals/Pets, 1999-2003; id135712 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arab-Americans, 1998-2003; id135713 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Art, 1998-2003; id135714 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Article List, 2006-2007; id135715 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charity, 2000-2004; id135716 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Children/Teens, 1998-2004; id135717 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Food, 1998-2003; id135718 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Global Issues, 1998, 2000,2002; id135719 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Health, 1998-2003; id135720 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History, 1998-2002; id135721 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Holidays, 2000, 2002; id135722 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Literature, 1998-2003; id135723 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Music, 1998, 2001-2002; id135724 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Nature, 2000-2001; id135725 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oak Trees, 1990; id135726 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Religion, 1999-2000, 2003, 2007-2009; id135727 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sports, 1998-2003; id135728 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Theater, 1998-2003; id135729 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Tips, 2002; id135730 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Various, 1998-2003; id135731 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Women, 1978, 1981, 1984, 1991-2004; id135732 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, id135657
  This series contains correspondence sent to Karkabi. Most of the materials consist of letters or emails concerning articles Karkabi wrote.
  - Addis Ababa Dogs, 2007; id135735 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Articles, 1986-1999, 2006-2009; id135736 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dr. Javed Aslam, 2006; id135737 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Association of Women Journalists, 1998-2000; id135738 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Awards, 1986-1999, 2008; id135739 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - “Baby Buddy to the Rescue”, 1988; id135740 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Books, 1996, 2005-2009; id135741 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Child Advocates, 1997; id135742 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Children’s Museum, 1989, 1997; id135743 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Danish Cartoons, 2006; id135744 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Ella Dobroski, 1987; id135745 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Doctor’s Orchestra, 2001; id135746 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Dogan Elementary School, 1987; id135747 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - England Trip, 2008; id135748 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Events, 1986-1988, 2000, 2007-2008; id135749 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Happing Website, 2007; id135750 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Hare Krishna, 2008; id135751 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Health Articles, 1986-1989, 1997, 1999, 2002-2005; id135752 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Hindu, 2006-2009; id135753 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - HITS Theatre, 2001; id135754 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Holidays, 1998, 2001, 2008; id135755 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Holocaust Museum, 2002, 2006; id135756 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Ann Hornak, 1989; id135757 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Houston Area Women’s Center, 1996, 2001; id135758 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Houston Chronicle, 2001-2009; id135759 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Alice Illian, 1998; id135760 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Judaism, 1988, 2006-2008; id135761 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - “Last Night at the Alamo", 1987; id135762 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - James Mattox, 1987; id135763 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Muslims, 1986, 2006-2009; id135764 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nuns, 1986, 2005-2007; id135765 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Organizations, 1986-1988, 1992, 2001-2002, 2007-2009; id135766 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - People, 1985-1988, 1992, 1999, 2000-2008; id135767 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Postcards, undated; id135768 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - “Prayers and Squares”, 2007; id135769 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Progressive Supranuclear Palsy, 2003; id135770 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Religion, 2005-2009; id135771 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Rachael Remen, 2000; id135772 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Riverside, 1987; id135773 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Felix Scardino, 2008; id135774 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Smile Store, 1996; id135775 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Spiderman Comic Book, 1986; id135776 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - St. Agnes Academy, 2000-2001; id135777 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “Stamp Out Stigma”, 2001; id135778 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Jim Stebbings, 2005, 2008; id135779 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Table Talk, 1998, 2004; id135780 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Thank You, 1986-1989, 1996, 2001; id135781 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Various, 1986-1990, 1996-2000, 2007-2008; id135782 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Appointment Books, id135658
  This series consists of day and monthly planners and message books. The monthly and day planners note appointments and scheduling, while the message books note missed calls. The day planner sub-series is incomplete with missing months for some years.
  - Day Planners, id135665
    - January-June 2000, id135784 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - July- December 2000, id135785 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - January-May 2001, id135786 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - June-September 2001, id135787 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - May-December 2002, id135788 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - January-August 2003, id135789 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - March, July-December 2004, id135790 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - January-March, November 2005, id135791 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - January-May 2006, id135792 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - July-December 2007, id135793 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - January-August 2008, id135794 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - September-December 2008, id135795 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Message Books, id135666
    - Message Book, undated; id135797 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Message Book, undated; id135798 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Message Book, undated; id135799 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Message Book, undated; id135800 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Message Book, undated; id135801 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Message Book, undated; id135802 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Monthly Planners, id135667
    - 2001, id135804 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 2002, id135805 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 2006, id135806 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 2007, id135807 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 2008, id135808 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Various, undated; id135809 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Houston Chronicle, id135659
  This series contains material directly related to the Houston Chronicle. Most of the material revolves around daily operations and internal issues of the paper. Also included are profiles and materials related to “Yo! Houston,” a feature on Houston teens.
  - Comments and Complaints, 2005; id135811 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2001, 2008; id135812 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Editorial Division Core Competencies, undated; id135813 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Expense Reports, 2001; id135814 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Goals, 2001; id135815 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hispanic Readers, undated; id135816 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - News Budget, May 12, 2007; id135817 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Folder not used, id135818 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Personal Vehicle Mileage Report, 2002; id135819 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Style Guides, undated; id135820 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - “Yo! Houston” Documents, undated; id135821 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - “Yo! Houston” Profiles, 2000; id135822 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - “Yo! Houston” Profiles Too Young, 2000; id135823 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - “Yo! Houston” Candidates, 2001; id135824 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - “Yo! Houston” Profiles, 2001; id135825 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - “Yo! Houston” Correspondence, 2006-2007; id135826 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Notes, id135660
  This series consists of Karkabi’s reporter’s notebooks. The notebooks have been divided by topic where any discernable topic is known. A large number of notebooks have been grouped into OVSBox 10.
  - Civil/Human Rights, undated; id135830 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - FEMA, undated; id135831 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Financial, undated; id135832 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Fort Davis, undated; id135833 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - C. Franklin, undated; id135834 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Health, undated; id135835 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hindu, undated; id135836 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hispanic Readership, undated; id135837 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ideas, undated; id135838 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Interview Questions, undated; id135839 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Iraq, undated; id135840 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Iranian Women, undated; id135841 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Islam, undated; id135842 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Israel 40th Anniversary, 1989; id135843 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mental Health, undated; id135844 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Mileage, 2001; id135845 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Philosophy, undated; id135846 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Religion, undated; id135847 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Religion, undated; id135848 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Religion, undated; id135849 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Religion, undated; id135850 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sources/Contacts, undated; id135851 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sudan, undated; id135852 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Various, undated; id135853 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Writing Tips, undated; id135854 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Notebooks, id176090 (Ovsbox 10, Item 1-36)
- Multi-Media, id135661
  This series contains audio, video, and photographic material related to Karkabi or her research. The majority of materials included do not revolve around Karkabi herself but with research for her articles. Included are photographs and an oral history with Mary Ann Kokernot Lacy conducted by Karkabi.
  - Audio, id135668
    - Folder not used, id135892 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Folder not used, id135893 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Oral History with Mary Ann Kokernot Lacy, 2010; id135894 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Folder not used, id135895 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Folder not used, id135896 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Photographic Material, id135669
    - Chronicle Building, undated; id135898 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Elizabeth Gregory, University of Houston Women’s Studies Program Director, 1995; id135899 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Folder not used, id135900 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Greater Zion Baptist Church, undated; id135901 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Barbara Karkabi Slide, undated; id135902 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Unknown Negatives, undated; id135903 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Various, undated; id135904 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Video, id135670
    - America at a Crossroads Press Screener DVD, undated; id135906 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Debra Duncan Show VHS, 2001; id135907 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Dominican Sisters of Houston 125th Anniversary Year DVD, 2007; id135908 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Secret Lives of Women S.4 E.5 “Polygamy Cult” DVD, 2008; id135909 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Witnessing Darfur, undated; id135910 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Publications, id135662
  This series consists of publications Karkabi collected for research for articles she wrote. The publications do not include any of Karkabi’s work. The majority of the material contained within the series relates to religious or health issues.
  - Art, id135671
    - Mike’s World, 2007; id135912 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Museum and Arts Magazine, February, April 1993; id135913 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Discrimination Committee, id135672
    - Newsletter, November 1985; id135915 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Newsletter, January, April, July, October 1986; id135916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Newsletter, September 1987; id135917 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Times, July, August, December 1985; id135918 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Catholic, id135673
    - Across The See, April 2008; id135920 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Calendario Histórico, 2009; id135921 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - The Catholic University of America Faculty Expert Guide, September 2007; id135922 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Conscience, Autumn 2007; id135923 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Conscience, Winter 2008-2009; id135924 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Order of Holy Mass, 2006; id135925 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Truth &Consequence, 2008; id135926 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Children’s Beat, id135674
    - Summer, 2000; id135928 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Summer, 2001; id135929 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Summer, 2002; id135930 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Fall, 2004; id135931 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - 2007/2008, id135932 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Christianity Today, id135675
    - March 2009, id135934 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - April 2009, id135935 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Faith & International Affairs, id135676
    - Vol. 4 No. 1, Spring 2006; id135937 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Vol. 5 No. 2, Summer 2007; id135938 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Ford Foundation, id135677
    - Ford Reports, 2007; id135940 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Report, Summer 2000; id135941 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Human Rights, id135678
    - ANERA News, Winter 2009; id135943 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Amalungelo Oluntu (Human Rights), 1991; id135944 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Houston Peace News, November-December 2007; id135945 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Houston Peace News, February-March 2008; id135946 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - New World Monthly, December 2001, January 2002; id135947 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - “Save Lebanon Update", Fall 1985; id135948 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - The Institute for Religion & Health, id135679
    - Health Caring, June, September-December 2006; id135950 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Health Caring, February, July, December 2007; id135951 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Islam, id135680
    - A Brief Illustrated Guide to Understanding Islam, 1997; id135953 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Islam, February 2002; id135954 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Islamic Horizons, July/August 2006; id135955 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Voice of Islam, April 1986; id135956 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - The Ismaili, id135681
    - Golden Jubilee, July 11, 2007; id135958 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Fatimid Art, March 21, 2008; id135959 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Journalism, id135682
    - Civic Catalyst, Spring 2001; id135962 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Civic Catalyst, Winter 2002; id135963 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - JAWS, Fall 1996; id135964 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Reporting on Religion, 2006; id135965 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Tragedies & Journalists, 2002; id135966 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Judaism, id135683
    - Jewish Herald-Voice, Spring 2006; id135973 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Jewish Herald-Voice, Fall 2006; id135968 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Jewish Herald-Voice, August 10, 2006; id135969 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Jewish Herald-Voice, October 12, 2006; id135970 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Jewish Herald-Voice, October 2007; id135971 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Moment, April 2006; id135972 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Mental Health, id135684
    - The Advocate, Summer, Winter 2001; id135975 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - New York City Voices, November/December 1997; id135976 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - New York City Voices, January-December 1998; id135977 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - New York City Voices, January/February 1999; id135978 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Psychotherapy Networker, March/April 2007; id135979 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Psychotherapy Networker, September/October 2007; id135980 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Psychology Today, June 2001; id135981 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - One Month to Live, id135685
    - Manuscript, 2007; id135983 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Press Kit, 2008; id135984 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Religion, id135686
    - Cenacle Retreat House, September 2007-August 2008; id135986 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Christian Events, July/August 2007; id135987 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Divya Yog Mandir, undated; id135988 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Faith & Freedom, undated; id135989 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Good News, Easter 2008; id135990 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Ink, Spring/Summer 2008; id135991 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - The Order of the Matins, undated; id135992 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Religion in the News, undated; id135993 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Texas Episcopalian, March 2007; id135994 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Universities, id135687
    - Circa, Winter 2009; id135996 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Shining Star, September 2008; id135997 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - The Source, 2008; id135998 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - University of St. Thomas Media Resource Guide, 2002-2003; id135999 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - UTMB Quarterly, Spring 2000; id136000 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Women, id135688
    - Ms., February 1989; id136002 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - New Voices, Fall 2008; id136003 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - The Red Book, 1997; id136004 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Success Sisters Solutions, January, March 1997; id136005 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Tidings, September 2002; id136006 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Windows of Opportunity, January 2005; id136007 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - A Woman’s Voice, 2000; id136008 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Various, id135689
    - Advocate News, Spring 2004; id136010 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Arte Público Complete Catalog, 2007; id136011 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Cite 72, Fall 2007; id136012 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Dallas Life Magazine, January 23, 1994; id136013 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - The Dallas Morning News, June 29, 1998; id136014 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Dateline Dubai, 2008; id136015 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Drinking and Driving, 1991; id136016 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Earth Ethics, Fall 2004; id136017 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Eat London, 2005; id136018 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Medallion, February 1992, January/February 1994; id136019 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - No Place for Hate, 2000; id136020 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Out Smart Vol 2. Issue 1, undated; id136021 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pursuing the Global Common Good, 2007; id136022 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - To Andrew, 1984; id136023 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Tracing Our Trails, 1993; id136024 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Vitality, October 2008; id136025 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Research, id135663
  This series contains materials Karkabi used for research purposes. The majority of the materials found in this series relate to religious or health issues. Karkabi did extensive research on Muslims as well as religious organizations and religious centers in the Houston area.
  - Events, id135699
    - 12th Annual James Luther Adams Forum on Religion and Society, 2008; id136027 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Book Releases, 2005-2009; id136028 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Career and Recovery Resources, Inc. Honors re. William and Mrs. Audrey Lawson, 2006; id136029 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Holidays, 2007-2008; id136030 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Icons from Sinai, 2006; id136031 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Israel 40th Anniversary, 1988; id136032 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - I Used to Have a Handle on Life But it Broke, 2002; id136033 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Kelly Day Conference, 2007; id136034 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Leadership for the 21st Century, 1998; id136035 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Lectures and Seminars, 2003, 2006-2009; id136036 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Lesbian Health Outreach, undated; id136037 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Lilly Endowment, 2008; id136038 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Look Beneath the Surface: Stop Modern Day Slavery Program Script, 2008; id136039 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Movies And Plays, 2002, 2005, 2007-2009; id136040 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Music, 1987, 2007-2009; id136041 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - NOW Convention, 1985; id136042 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Pluralism Project, 2008; id136043 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - The Prayers & Squares Quilt Ministry, 2000; id136044 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Save Sam Rethu, undated; id136045 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Second Chance, Second Act, 2007; id136046 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Sister D’s Labyrinth, undated; id136047 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Take Our Daughters to Work Day, 1995; id136048 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Various, 1998-2009; id136049 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Voices Breaking Boundaries, 2001; id136050 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - The Waiting Room, 2000; id136051 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Health, id135700
    - Autism, 2004; id136053 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Battering During Pregnancy, 1985; id136054 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Breast Cancer, 1971, 2000; id136055 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Endometriosis, undated; id136056 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Leprosy/Hansen’s Disease, 1985; id136057 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Mental Health, 1998-2002, 2005; id136058 (Box 6, Folder 47)